This is about some websites that the CIA made around 2010.
They were used for their assets,
the people that recruited or coerced
in target countries like Iran and China
to spy on those countries.
These were the websites that those people would give
what they spied back to the CIA.
And those are exposed.
And one of them was Star Wars themed,
which is kind of cool.
Before those websites were uncovered,
I'd heard rumors that many, many CIA agents
in China had been caught.
This 2018 article was a major thing,
but we didn't know how.
It was starting to emerge
that some public websites are compromised,
but we didn't know any examples.
When I heard about this, I'm interested in Chinese politics.
and I said, oh, do you know any of them?
I even asked on Quora and Chris, engineer and former technician
at the US Navy said, you're dumb.
Obviously, the CIA is so smart,
they would never leak their websites.
Well, Chris, fast forward to 2022,
and an article emerged with a few links.
So I only heard about this in 2023.
I was browsing YouTube and this video popped up
from Darknet Diaries.
I didn't watch the video, I just clicked the link
and that's it.
So it's a Reuters article where some of the ex spies
were complaining that the CIA didn't treat them well.
The CIA used us and dumped us
and they gave a few websites.
This is an example of one of the websites that was used.
This is a reconstruction from the Reuters article.
As you'd expect, there's a login field
where the agent would go and type a password
and would use encryption to talk to the CIA.
But Reuters only gave two URLs directly on the article
but they also gave like seven or eight screenshots in total.
From those screenshots, it was rather easy
to find out all the domains, the seven or eight domain names
because either they were on the type of the page,
this is one of the pages.
Or if you expected the page source,
the URL for the images had websites.
So this active gaming info.com, this Chinese website
was one of the websites.
So they basically gave away seven or eight websites.
But they also said that they had found upwards of 350
or 800 or something of that websites.
And when I read that, I was like,
oh, it would be cool if you could find a bunch of them, right?
But they didn't disclose them
because they didn't want to cause trouble to the agents.
But I said, okay, I'm gonna try anyways,
it's been 10 years, let's do it.
The coolest things that I found,
one, the Star Wars website, was pretty awesome
because most of the websites are extremely boring
and didn't have pop culture references like this.
The Reuters article basically gave all those
that have pop culture references,
but they missed this one and I'm really really glad
because I'm the one to reveal it.
So this is awesome.
And the other cool thing and much more serious
is the USA spying on its allies.
And by allies, I mean democracies,
which we know, of course, are not really allies.
For example, Brazil, we know which country
those websites target because of the language.
Some languages could be many countries,
but other language could only be one country.
For example, Brazilian Portuguese, they were spying Brazil.
Snowden had already talked about this
and there are many other relations.
We know they spied in Brazil,
but it's really cool that you get this
Wayback Machine image.
You have an actual link.
You can see it's live on this link
in the Wayback Machine and you can see the websites
more or less as they were, so that's kind of cool.
Germany, the Dedrick Online.
I don't speak German, but it's German.
France, Le Summum De la Finance,
I speak French.
Italy, Atività Estremi.
And many other democracies.
So it's kind of cool.
Now I'll just talk a little bit about
how I found the new websites
that are not given by Reuters.
So the first and easy thing was
they used sequential IPs for the websites
and Reuters themselves mentioned that.
From that, it's quite easy to find other websites.
It's just a question of how good is your data.
Because the websites are down now,
so it has to be historic data.
The first website that I found
some easily accessible on the web browser,
historic data, was this one, viewdns.info.
It's not complete by any means.
I pieced data from many sources,
but this one, was the easiest one to use,
The first one I found on Google
and I found some new domains and I was quite excited.
I took activegaminginfo.com.
So if you go there, you can do an IP history
and you can see, oh, for this domain,
what are all the IPs that have served that domain?
And so here we found out 2012,
this is one of the IPs that served that domain.
2024, don't care, 2012, yeah, that's the one.
And then you take that IP,
there's another tool which searches,
for this IP, what are all the domains
that have been historically hosted on that IP?
If you search one by one in the browser,
but then they have an API,
you can find other nearby IPs
and that's how I found my first hits.
So here, for example, in a nearby IP like 149,
this was the 148
so the next one had a likely hit.
And then if you take the domain name,
you can go on the Wayback Machine
and you can confirm this has some similarities
with the others, so it's definitely a hit.
The problem with the Wayback Machine
is that you have to have the domain name,
they don't have any IP exposed,
they have the data, but they don't expose it.
So we have to do other sources to find the domains.
Okay, so that was the easy part.
The hard part is finding new IP ranges.
Then I tried a bunch of random stuff.
The first way I found new hits on new ranges
was through the 2013 DNS census,
which is published on this random Neocities website
and it was very likely to obtained via an illegal botnet.
Because it's quite similar to a 2012 botnet dump like this.
So some guy hacked a bunch of routers
and then instead of using them to do something evil,
the guy used them to explore the net
and publish the data publicly,
which is amazing, this guy is awesome.
But it's unknown who published this, he's anonymous.
And their data looks like this, as you'd expect.
They really went for all each IPv4,
they were pinging every single IPv4 ever
because IPv4 you could do that still with a botnet.
And just selecting a few random domains,
amazon.com, on this date
was served at this IP. And they have that
for all that they could find.
Then I took that, I dumped it into SQLite,
which is a local SQL database, which I love so much.
It's so cool.
And started mining that and trying to find new domains.
One of the main things that helps,
part of the fingerprint to help identify the sites
was that the CIA use exclusively almost dedicated servers.
So you have one site per IP.
And this is the case for not many websites.
At least nowadays, at the time I'm not sure,
but at the time I think too, they were a minority
so that makes it easier to find them.
With this datasets, you have to search
which IP only has one domain,
so that narrows things down a bit.
The other thing that I used, the Wayback Machine API,
Those websites, they had four communication mechanisms.
Jar, Adobe Flash, JavaScript, HTTPS.
Yes, HTTPS, it's true.
And each one of those has certain URL patterns
on the path part of the URL,
and that's how they communicate.
In the Wayback Machine, you cannot search in cross domains,
which is a shame.
You can only search for this domain,
does it have this path?
So we need to have a big domain list.
By using heuristics, I started narrowing down a bit
and I managed to find a few others.
And then I noticed, oh, the Wayback Machine does not block Tor.
I scripted 100 Tor IPs,
to speed things up 100x, that helped a lot.
Basically, there's a funnel and you start narrowing down
more and more likely hits,
and then you just look at them manually at some point.
And the other thing which was major
and is very cheeky and very heuristic
is one third of the hits contains the word
"news" on the domain name.
And I used that heuristic and it was extremely effective.
So when I started finding some new hits,
I was put them on Google from time and time
and see if other websites have that domain
because they might have other of the hits.
There's a few that appeared on Chinese expired domain trackers,
which are websites that track for this date,
2012, March 6th, those domains expired.
I think the goal of those websites
is for commercial uses, to sell the domains afterwards.
But I used them.
They were highly throttled,
but with some patience, I scraped them all
and I put it on GitHub, another little data set
and contribution to the community, which is kind of cool.
Finally, I'm not an expert on any of this,
I just Googled them, tried stuff out.
If you have any historic data sources,
because those websites are down now,
so historic data sources or any ideas
of the print fingerprints, let me know.
If you find something, you will be extremely clearly credited
on the article and on Twitter.