Bitcoin inscription museum. I learned that you can write arbitrary data into the
Bitcoin blockchain, non-financial data. For example, images and text. And that's
kind of cool, because the Bitcoin blockchain is distributed to many, many people, so
it's very hard to delete the data. The question that comes to mind then is how
illegal does something have to be for some government to say "Bitcoin is illegal
in this country"? Are Pedobear memes illegal enough? What about nuclear
weapon designs? This is from Reddit, by the way, it's all speculation. CIA don't come after me.
What about political memes? If you post a Tankman meme in China. Do they like it? I don't think anything is
illegal enough. Either there's always a better way to find illegal things or your
enemies have already saved any leaks that happened in their servers and
it is already too late. So I don't think it will ever get banned. But this inspiration led me to
really investigate things a bit and it's just kind of cool what I found, not
necessarily illegal things, but just people. Bitcoin started in 2009. In 2022,
Ordinal Ruleset Inscriptions, a protocol for writing stuff on the blockchain was created
and it became really, really popular. As you can see here, nowadays there are more
than 400,000 of such inscriptions, which are mostly images. So at this point, you
cannot see all of them, but in the earlier days, when Bitcoin was less popular,
there were way, way fewer images. So my kind of obsession has been, I'm gonna find all
the images. Which kind of means searching in many heuristic ways, because there's
multiple ways that you can encode things. Is it a raw PNG? Is it base 64? So it's
hard to find all of them, but I'm getting close to it. And it's cool because I saw
what people put in there and I appreciated it. There was almost nothing
illegal and a lot of fun things. So basically, social media, it's basically
what they use it for. So fun tributes, like a Magic the Gathering and trading card
game card ASCII art. These are just two friends and they created the earliest
protocol basically for upload. And one of them is really cool, EMBII who replies on
Twitter and is really nice. It was cool to see what those people are doing in
the early days. So this is also an upload by EMBII. This is a photography
that he created himself. He just found a little art of a robot on the street and
took a picture of it and put it on Bitcoin blockchain. The idea behind it is
that this robot will disappear. This image will stay in the blockchain forever.
The art is a bit beyond just the image. It's where it is placed. It's placed on
the Bitcoin blockchain and this adds a context to it. It was kind of cool. Stupid
memes. Of course, part of social media. Love declarations. So this one has a novel
Chinese poem, Western man married to the Chinese woman. And ads. There's this
conference, GRR conference, "get your free GRR CON code". Oh, but where is it? And then
at some point, oh, we should remove the at signs because there's a bunch of at
signs. It becomes much clearer "OP_RETURN is your friend". So when I saw
this, I was like OH OH, like a little obfuscation puzzle. Yeah. So it was really fun to
explore this kind of things.