Hi I'm Ciro Santilli and just wanted to get a few things off my chest. I've been meaning to say
those things online for a while now. But many many things happened I got busy so before I
start my new job I want to take the chance to do it now. The first thing that I'd like to talk
about is the status of the failed mostly OurBigBook project so as a recap I received a one thousand
Monero donation last year to do the project for one year and I have done it mostly. That was about
100,000 pounds and more or less equivalent to one year salary that I would have had at the time.
I have already made a text post about this, but it felt like such a large donation deserved a little
video so, in summary, I did not get a single user for the project except myself.
This is somewhat expected, there are two things that I could have done: one is better tech
and the other would have been actually going after users by making content. Perhaps I should have done
content, but I did just a tech. Partly because I'm a nerd, and afraid of human contact. A little bit.
A little bit of laziness perhaps as well but the tech features were not easy and I do feel that some of them were
fundamental and maybe in the future one day they will actually lead to the project actually taking off. Maybe.
In terms of tech, I have focused on improving the OurBigBook Web website which is the component of the project where it's intended that multiple users
would collaborate on any subject that they want and it's basically the major innovation of the project.
OurBigBook Web has become much more stable and some of the features that I wanted that felt really
really cool and necessary I've done them. I've also done some which were more experimental and they took more
time than they should have taken because everything is harder than you think. But I did them you know.
Everything is harder than it seems at first and I greatly respect web developers.
Every time I have a web development experience it greatly increases my respect for web devs.
And my hatred for them for making such shitty frameworks at times. But also my respect for them. Yeah, it's not easy,
making a dynamic website. Besides the dynamic website I have also improved a little bit the static
website generation. I do feel that OurBigBook is a very good, at least for me, I made essentially
the perfect way for myself to take notes. I do think that was achieved and also the static website
generation is exactly what I wanted and the way you take notes is exactly what I wanted and one of the
major points which I wanted and I think I achieved is the ability for users to have one table of contents
with all their knowledge infinitely deep table of contents and where you can just go on and
go deeper and deeper and deeper and deeper (oh that's a nice apple) you can go deeper and deeper and deeper
into any subject that you want to any degree. And I do realize that part of the project's failure
is that this is such a niche desire that very few people, I imagine, want to take a subject and
rip the heck out of it you know. Just document everything there is to document on the subject.
But this is what I want and for quite a few subjects. And doing so for free you know. So this is a niche
thing. But I knew that from the start. And it's what we've all heard: that for user generated content
there is a very small number of people who generate a large amount of content and huge value. So I
knew that. The question is finding those people and convincing them that you have the the best platform
for them to do that on. Which so far I have failed. But there is hope that one day I'll manage to
convince someone. There is hope, we'll see. So that's a summary of what happened. I was doing the
tech tech features and I didn't really directly outreach to university students which would have been the
the primary primary niche users that I had in mind. And basically to acquire
them I would have had to, I think, help them study for the university courses. Which is something
that I would still want to try and do. Because the whole reason for me doing this website is that
when I was at uni, and at school, I felt it could all be so much better and better explained you
know. So I do think it would be, if I didn't need money, I might actually do that you know. I'm really kind
of burned out of doing tech features (without active users). If I had more time for the project I don't think I'd do any more tech
features immediately. I would really focus exclusively on building a community and yeah I would give this
a serious try. Which would be of the likes you know: go to a nearby university which I have I'm
currently in Oxford. But I'm moving soon. And then decide for a course like
mathematics physics, these are the obvious choices. And then pick the course and try to
help the students do the courses and learn the courses as well as possible. I did research this a
lot like what would be the best course to go after. And at least in Oxford the mathematics course seems
like the easiest choice. The main reason is because of how open it is. They're putting all their
lecture notes and exercise sheets online more and more. And that is something to be very respected.
And in some cases even the solutions, they're trying to you know upload solutions themselves. Which would
somewhat compete with what I would be doing. But I do believe that with a exclusive focus on helping
the students you know we would be able to create better educational content. And that's what I
wanted to to try, like exclusive focus on the students. Which is not what most faculty have of course they
they have to do research and they're extremely pressured for novel results. So
I do think if I had more time one more year it would be worth giving that a shot. I think it is risky
business. Part of me also feels that maybe I'd be wasting my life and I could be doing something better
as well. But I don't think it's something has ever been done. Some students have you know taken amazing
lecture notes and tried to cover as much as possible. But I do believe that being a student you're already
under so much pressure to pass the bloody exams that you know you can only do so much. So someone external
with a deep interest in the subject and a deep empathy towards the students trying to do that
I'm not sure it has ever been done to the level that I might be able to do. So it is an interesting
experiment. So I did go to the mathematics institute of the university of Oxford, which I'm very grateful
for them being so open. They have a cafe downstairs and you could go into lecture rooms if you wanted you
know watch some courses. I'm kind of old I think they'd look weird at me but I'd get away with it
I think. so I do get you know somewhat access to the students and did work there many many times. So I
did get watch to their movements and understand more which courses they are taking. But I didn't directly reach
out to them. The bar is quite high right: they're smart. So I would need something quite good not to be
you know, so they don't think I'm completely weird and worthless. But, it could be met I think, and
if I had met the bar on a course I would want to try and advertise it. I don't know how it is a difficult
question. but I mean put a note in front of my laptop here's a solved version of this course X
link to it online any question talk to me for free. I don't know you know they have hundreds of
students maybe one or two pick it up and see that I'm amazing who knows. It's just a bit of a hail mary but
it should be worth trying. Another thing that I should mention is that my personality
is being lazy. I am the lazy guy that Bill Gates talks about, that should get the hard task.
So I never push myself to burnout ever and that has ups and downs. What it means basically
is that I just keep doing the thing if it's interesting for a long time you know. And whatever
I have a deep interest on eventually I get it you know but it's not fast. So it's not like I was
doing the projects 12 hours a day every day. But I did do it seriously. But I also you know sometimes
how to take time off to look after my family. Another thing that I did which detracted me a little bit
from the project was a few small not so small side projects. It is a bit ridiculous that I should do
side projects when I'm doing basically my dream project. But it is also part of my personality.
I just had to do this kind of thing, otherwise I get too too tired of a given
subject. One thing particular that I did was pushing the CIA Covert Communication Websites research
a little bit further. And that did reach the you know had a web article on the Daily Mail so I think
it was worth it you know to get my name out there, potentially reach new people.
But I was always conscious that I should be getting back to OurBigBook now.
It was just in this case I was doing that project a little bit obsessively because
it felt that it was something actually big and novel and it is I do believe one of my most
departed contributions to the world so far. So I think it was worth it, time will tell.
As for the future of the OurBigBook project. Immediately what's gonna happen now is I'm gonna
start a new job quite soon and I don't plan on doing any major features or content in the
foreseeable future. I will keep the website running and I plan to run keep it running for as long as I
live. It costs currently I think 16 dollars a month so I can handle that. And I will
continue to continue to use OurBigBook as my primary note-taking and publication mechanism.
I'm flexible in the sense that if there's another place where it's better to publish things where
it will be seen, more likely to be seen, I will use that and perhaps just link it to it from OurBigBook.
But for broader subjects which other websites such as Stack Overflow and Wikipedia don't cover
well, which is basically the the gap that OurBigBook was intended to fill, then the bulk will go into
OurBigBook. So this is the immediate future. We'll see maybe one day I'll pick up some university
courses here and there and try to solve them, and see if it generates some interest. But not planning
on doing that immediately, I'm gonna be starting a new job and I want to focus on that.
About the new job, it is you know, still low-level tech. I will be moving out of Oxford
but the new location, in the UK, is also whole home to a major university, so that does open some
doors potentially. It's not very likely but there is a potential that this will help.
About potential future donations which, if someone is crazy enough donates to a failure such as me,
I have clarified on a text post I cannot accept anonymous donations anymore as I have for
this a thousand Monero donation, which is a shame but it's the way society works. There is
essentially no way of preventing money laundering if you allow anonymous donations. In my case for example
sometimes I think, wow like if I were a drug dealer and I just donated this money to myself, I'm currently
getting away with it. You know. I did program a lot and I have lots of GitHub comments I don't think
a drug dealer would have been able to. But I did get away with it, so far. As I made a text post about,
much earlier, Barclays had frozen my account for a week earlier, then I started
diversifying my accounts like crazy and much more recently they said: okay no more anonymous donations
or us will kick you out. So I don't expect that to be different for any other British bank.
So at least for the time being, while I will accept anonymous donations, I will not count them towards
if "I get X then I do Y calculations". I should also mention that although the amount that I
received was I mean amazing and extremely generous and I'm extremely thankful for it and equivalent to
a year's salary, of course when you do a failed project like this, it does put you in a worse
position than where you started off financially, a little bit. So for example my new job
will be paid 10% less than my previous one, two years ago. So I do take a little bit of a
hit, and I have a family which I have to take care of right, they're amazing and they have support
for me to some degree. So that has to be taken consideration. So I wouldn't be able to take
anymore like one year's salary right, it has to be much more. So it's this is something that has
to be considered. So it cannot be anonymous and it has to be more than your salary I don't know how much,
and just besides the money, this also degrades employees confidence in hiring you
because you know if you're really good and you might be getting more money to do something,
I might you know work for them for a while and then leave, which of course understandably is not
not great for employers because you know bringing bringing people up to speed is a considerable cost
and I understand that you know. But so asking for donations online does take a hit on your
employability. This time it was somewhat tough, I'd say, I didn't apply for any job, I only went for things
which I had some degree of interest in, which is low-level tech low-level semiconductor tech basically.
But even within that for which I have various levels of qualifications depending on the job it, wasn't
easy. I got like a lot of rejections. It's hard to quantify this kind of stuff but I do suspect
that this played a role, I have been asked "oh would you leave us if you should get another donation" and I
said "yes if it's enough I will leave you" obviously as with anyone. But in my case there is a greater
probability that this will actually happen. So these are things that have to be taken into account.
Another contributing factor to the difficulty of job search is that I think a lot
of the world resources have been pulled into LLMs. I do think there's some merit to
that, I am quite excited about you know LLM usage in mathematics and really trying to achieve AGI. I do
strongly believe that you already have enough computational power for AGI, so what I
call and I think others might call the "hexaflop hypothesis" that once you have hexaflops
of computation that's enough to simulate the brain, because "how many neurons you have times
how many synapses each neuron has times how many times per second they fire" and that is a hexaflop.
So I do think there's a merit certain merit to going there maybe, to novel architectures not just
LLMs, but I'm not qualified in that and no one gave me a job on that. I did apply to some
companies. I do feel that companies are very, they can only evaluate how many years of experience you have
and what's your university. They are not able to evaluate you know your projects meaningfully. So
this is also which is something that I have right. Being a top this year you likely end up in top 18 or 17
year user on Stack Overflow for example, which is a notable achievement I would say. But most recruiters
don't take that into account. My current job did actually so I'm very thankful to them. It's not the
most exciting thing ever but it is good enough and there is a genuine degree of interest in doing
it. I've concluded that what I really need is I'll insert here now the name of the this is American
fellowship which pays 800 000 for creative people [MacArthur Fellowship] but they have to be in the US but that sounded like
the right one for me.
I should also mention that if you want to make things easy you could just donate a "I can retire
type for donation". I will do exclusively open projects until I die, open stem projects until I die if that
happens. Half joking here [such donation feels unlikely] but I mean I would do that. The exact amount is a tough question, it depends on
taxation, maybe four million to be very very on the safe side. So after tax two. Housing prices are
crazy right now in the places where people want to live. One million pounds for a house and then one
one million to invest in S&P 500 and live forever. That's kind of the goal. Another financial remark
semi-jokingly but is that I also feel kind of bad falling behind my peers financially a little bit.
I'm not destitute but I'm falling behind the hard-working peers that need perhaps more money than me.
It's kind of sad. So moving forward if I get any free time which is not likely in the immediate
term but maybe as I settle more into my job, I would be interested into looking into some higher tech
things, and I'm what I'm most passionate about I think would be trying to achieve AGI, or a little step
towards it. It's just too mind-blowing the fact that we might be able to actually achieve it in our
lifetimes, it is just too mind-blowing. This was my broad intention since I was doing my
undergrad you know in 2012 and 13 I made some choices toward the direction but I didn't push
hard enough. I also made some choices toward GPUs in 2015-16 but again didn't push for long enough
slash hard enough. I'd be retired by now if I had. So, I what I mean to say is of, course there
is this AI boom, which kind of peaks my interest as well, but I do have a genuine interest in that
area which kind of predates the current AI boom. Just I didn't push it hard enough as maybe I should
have. got a little bit distracted with education, which is I'm also extremely passionate about.
Within that area two aspects which I'd like to research on are one is
maths and code generation, because it it does feel that my job is dumb, most a programmer's job is dumb
most of the time, and it feels so automatable and there have been major progresses. I haven't fully
evaluated all the code generation mechanisms yet, but the general feeling is sometimes you
one shot problems and it's like oh my goodness I'm so glad, but others and for more complex problems,
which involve more internal data, which the model has not been trained on, for those they fail and once they
fail the first time they can't move forward, so you end up wasting more time trying to
prompt, than you if you were just solving the problem yourself. But I do believe that there's
even for not very useful things like you know pure mathematics or Project Euler problems
you know coding / mathematics computational problems, I do feel that there's an extreme beauty into
automatically solving that, and it is definitely a way to measure part of our progress towards AGI.
I would also be interested in doing more robotics oriented things I did consider applying for
jobs in the area but again no one would hire me because I have zero experience, but I have done a little
side project on that and I do have a gut feeling like many other people that
maybe having some robotics intuition in your models is going to be key towards AGI. I don't know, maybe not
but feels possible and worthwhile exploring. So that's another area which, through simulations
because who wants to deal with real robots right that's for losers, so with simulations mostly I think
that'll be very exciting. I'm also quite excited by the potential of doing ARC-AGI problems I won't have
the time for that unfortunately but it is quite intriguing to me because it does feel like some
problems which are very easy for humans to solve, untrained humans, essentially, maybe
standard western high school students, but still computers are struggling to solve them so
solving ARC-AGI would be also pretty cool. But on the other hand also there are so many
early retired finance and big tech bros doing that already that I don't know if I should compete with
them [https://ourbigbook.com/cirosantilli/arc-agi-is-a-black-hole-for-early-retired-tech-and-finance-bros]
but it is a worthwhile pursuit I guess. If I were to ever do any more tech for the OurBigBook project
which is not what I would do initially, I don't believe that any tech unless you add AGI to it, is
going to be enough to attract users by itself, but if one day I were to add more features there are two
major outstanding features which would be quite cool to implement. They're not rocket science but
they are considerable which is what you see what you get editing and and being able to pull changes
back. So WYSIWYG would be you know both a local and the web maybe, something like Trillium Notes. I find
that pro project extremely interesting and feature wise so many interesting features, and maybe even
forking that, add support for OurBigBook markdown and restrict some of this less wieldy features. So that's one of
them, and that would greatly increase accessibility. For me it's not so bad because I'm so familiar with the
markup but when dealing with images for mathematical formulae, yeah I know having WYSIWYG even for me I
missed that. You know so I get it you know WYSIWYG is is worth one's time you know. And the other thing,
the thing about pulling changes back from OurBigBook Web so basically what that means is currently you can
write local files and push those files to Web, but if you edit on Web which is possible, there's no way to
pull those changes back and merge them without potentially losing your local stuff, so doing
that is would require to some extent implementing git or a git-like mechanism.
The initial version of OurBigBook was a GitLab fork, but I abandoned that, I think wisely,
trying to focus more first on the more innovative aspects of the project,
not get too bogged down git and existing code bases. But I do miss git now for that.
It's not so easy because locally you know on Web everything is split to the header and locally you
can have source files which have multiple headers, so this does require some thought it's not just
slapping git in twitter and end of story but it's not rocket science and could be inspired by git.